Guide to the Bruce Boling Irish Language Papers AIA.062
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Research Files
  - Subseries IB. Irish Immigrants in the Land of New Canaan, 1959-2001
    - Letters: Magrath, Thomas William, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Letters: Magraw, James, circa 1980-2001 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Letters: Mahon, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Letters: Makemie, Francis, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Letters: Mallen, Bernard, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Letters: Maloney family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Letters: Mangan Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Letters: Martin Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Letters: Martyn, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Letters: Masterson, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Letters: Maveety, Patrick, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Letters: McArthur, Robert, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Letters: McBride, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Letters: McCann/Clarke Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Letters: McCarthy Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Letters: McCarty, Daniel, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Letters: Mclellard, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Letters: McCobb, Samuel, circa 1980-2001 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Letters: McConnel, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Letters: McCormack, Ross, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters: McCormick, John and Ann, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters: McCoy Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters: McCullagh, Peter, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters: McCulloch, David, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Letters: McCulloch/Hutchinson (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters: McCulloch/Hutchinson (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Letters: McCulloch/Hutchinson (III): Language, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters: McCulloch/Montgomery/Hutchinson Families, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters: McCullough, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letters: McCurtin, Daniel, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Letters: McCusker/McDonald Families, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Letters: McDermott, Michael, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Letters: McEldemy Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Letters: McElroy, William (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Letters: McElroy, William (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Letters: McFadden, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Letters: McFarland Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Letters: McGiffert Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Letters: McGonigle Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Letters: McGoogan Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Letters: McGavock, Hugh, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Letters: McGraw, Alexander, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Letters: McGregor: Rev. James and John McMurpy, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Letters: McGuinness/Elliott Families, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Letters: McHenry/Moore Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Letters: McHugh, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Letters: McIntyre, T., circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Letters: M'Kenna, Bernard, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Letters: McKeown Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Letters: McMahon, John, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Letters: McMahon, Tighe, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Letters: McMahon, Thomas; Sotherin, William; Justice, John, circa 1980-2001 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Letters: McMullen, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Letters: McNabb, Ann [Irish Cook], circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Letters: McNair Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Letters: McNally, Edward, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Letters: McNally, Mrs. P., circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Letters: McNish, Alexander, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Letters: McSparron Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Letters: Mellon, Thomas, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Letters: Melville Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Letters: Miller, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Letters: Mitchell/McFarland Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Letters: Mitchell Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Letters: Moffatt, Robert (I), circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Letters: Moffatt, Robert (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Letters: Montgomery Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Letters: Moore Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Letters: Moore, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Letters: Moore, S. O., circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Letters: Moore, Thomas, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Letters: Mulligan, James A., 1973-2000 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Letters: Mulligan/Martin Families, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Letters: Murphy Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Letters: Murphy Family (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Letters: Murphy, Michael J., circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Letters: Murrray Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Letters: Nevin, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Letters: Nevin, John (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Letters: Newport, Sir John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Letters: Nicholl, George, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Letters: Nolan Family [Kilkenny}, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Letters: Nolan, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Letters: Nolan, M., circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Letters: Nolan, William, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Letters: Nowlan Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Letters: O'Brien, Andrew Leary, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Letters: O'Brien, William Smith, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Letters: O'Callaghan Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Letters: O'Connell, Charles U., circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Letters: O'Connor, Charles, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Letters: O'Connor, Batt, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Letters: O'Connor, Jerry, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Letters: O'Daly, Hugh, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Letters: O'Donohue Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Letters: O'Hagan, Charles and Mary Dunn, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Letters: [O']Hanlan Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Letters: O'Hara, Charles, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Letters: O'Kelly, John, circa 1980-2001 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Letters: O'Neil, P., circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Letters: O'Neill, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Letters: O'Neill, Robert, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Letters: O'Raw, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Letters: O'Reilly, Henry, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Letters: Orr, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Letters: O'Sullivan, Lawrence, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Letters: Parke, Robert, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Letters: Parker, Pat, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Letters: Patten, Matthew, circa 1970-2000 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Letters: Patton, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Letters: Personel, Francis Burdett, circa 1980-2000 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Letters: Phillips, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Pillson, Robert, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Polin, Daniel, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters: Porter Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters: Quirk Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Quirn, William, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters: Redick, David and Aedanus Burke, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters: Reilly, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters: Revell-Whitridge Family (I), circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters: Revell-Whitridge Family (II), circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters: Richey Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Letters: Robinson, David, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Letters: Ruisséal, Michéal, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Letters: Sheil, Christopher J., circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Letters: Shepherd Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letters: Shipboy Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Letters: Sinclair Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Binder (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Binder (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Binder (III), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Binder (IV), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Binder (V), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Census Materials, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Civil War Letters, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Family Background and Research, circa 1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: General (I), circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: General (II), circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: General (III), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Grammatical Features (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Grammatical Features (II), circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Lexicon, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Linguistic Features, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Phonology: General, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Phonology: Manuscript Excerpts, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Phonology: Raising of /o/ and /e/, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Placenames and Maps, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Spelling of Vowels, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Letters: Sproule, Andrew: Verbal Morphology, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Letters: Steele Family Biographical Information, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Letters: Steele, Ephraim, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Letters: Steele, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Letters: Stewart Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Letters: Taylor Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Letters: Tenney[?], Bridget, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Letters: Thompson-Mullen Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Letters: Toal, James and Mary, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Letters: Toner, Edward and Mary, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Letters: Tracy, James Francis, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Letters: Valentine, George, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Letters: Waldron, Thomas, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Letters: Vicira, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Letters: Walsh, Mary McLean, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Letters: Walsh, Patrick Kieran, circa 1970-2000 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Letters: Wansbrough, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Letters: Warden, David Bailie, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Letters: White, Jane, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Letters: Wildes, Mary, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Letters: Williams, Rose, circa 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Letters: Williamson, William, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Willcocks, Joseph, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Wilson Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters: Witherow, Joseph, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters: Witherspoon Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Witherspoon Genealogy, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters: Witherspoon, Robert, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters: Woolsey, Francis, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters: Woulfe, Maurice, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters: Woulfe, Maurice (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters: Woulfe, Maurice (III), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Letters: Wright Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters: Wright, Joseph, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters: Wright, Joseph and Hannah, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Letters: Wright, Margaret, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Letters: Wright, Margaret (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Letters: Wylly-Habersham, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Letters: Young, Arthur, circa 1980-2000 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Letters: [Unidentified] (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Letters: [Unidentified] (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Letters: [Unidentified] (III), circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Letters: [Unthank?], G., circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - List of Possible Libraries and Archives, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Maps, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Notes: Irish Parish Surname, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Notes Regarding Migration of an Entire Congregation from Ireland to Salem, New York, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - O'Buachalla, Liam Biographical Information, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Perfect Participle and Infinitive Notes, circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Research Trip Data, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Reviews, circa 2003 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Song of Farewell to Young Immigrants", circa 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Transparencies, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Series II. Original Writings and Presentations, 1972-1995
  This series contains materials related to Boling's original writings or presentations delivered at various conferences. Materials include manuscripts, handouts, and transparencies. Topics include the evolution of the Irish language, the value of studying letters with regards to researching dialect, and the history of Irish immigration from a socio-linguistic perspective.
  - "A Bibliography of the Irish Immigration to North America", undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "Comparative Indo-European Relion: A Bibliographical Guide", undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - "The Death of the Irish Language: Emigration as 'Murder Machine'" Proposal, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Irish Culture and Irish Emigration to North America: Typescript, Jul 17, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Irish Culture and Irish Emigration to North America: Copyright, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Irish Culture and Irish Emigration to North America: Annotated Typescript, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "The Geography of an Irish Letter: Letter Writing and Dialect in 19th-Century Ulster", Oct 12, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "A Hiberno-English Dialect of West Tyrone", undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "Irish Emigration and the Decline of Gaelic Culture in Ireland", undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - "Irish Emigration and the Popular Image of America in Ireland", undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - "Irish Language and Behavior: A Sketch", undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - "Language and World View in Traditional Ireland," American Conference of Irish Studies; Dublin, Ireland, Jun 28-Jul 14, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - "Language and World View in Traditional Ireland," American Conference of Irish Studies; Dublin, Ireland, Jun 28, 1987-Jul 4, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Notes on Phonology and Grammatical Features for Adams Paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Old Irish Sebortir," Studia Celtica, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Senchus Már: The Oldest Fragments", Oct 25, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Out of Ireland We Have Come: A Study in Progress of Letters of irish Immigrants to America", Jun 1, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Some of the Problems of the Phonology and Morphology of the Old Irish Verb", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Use of the Letters in the Study of Dialect," Queens University of Belfast, May 16, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series III. Secondary Source Materials, 1905-2001
  This series contains bibliographies and scholarly journal articles on a variety of historical and linguistic subjects, ranging from general to specific. Many of the linguistic articles relate to grammatical, morphological, or phonological phenomena present in a particular language. The materials in this series represent scholarly journal articles related to the immediate areas of Boling's research interests - the historical evolution of the Irish language and English dialects in Ireland - in addition to historical linguistics topics present in a wide-range of languages, including French, German, Russian, Navajo, and Ukrainian.
  - Adams, G. B. "An Introduction to the Study of Ulster Dialects." Proceedings of the Royal Irish Academy, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Adams, G. B. "The Phonology of the Antrim Dialect: Part I" Proceedings of the Royal Irish Academy, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Albrecht, Erhard. "Aktuelle Fragen in den Wechselbeziehungen von Sprache und Denken." Deutsche Zeitschrift Fuer Philosophie, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Andersen, Henning. "Abductive and Deductive Change." Language, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Andersen, Henning. "Morphological Change: Towards a Typology." Historical Morphology, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Andersen, Henning. "Perceptual and Conceptual Factors in Abductive Innovations." Trends in Linguistics: Studies and Monographs, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Anderson, Stephen R. "Historical Change and Rule Ordering in Phonology." Trends in Linguistics: Studies and Monographs, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Anderson, Stephen R. "On the Description of Consonant Gradation in Fula." Studies in African Linguistics, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Antilla, Raimo. "The Acceptance of Sound Change by Linguistic Structure." Trends in Linguistics: Studies and Monographs, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Babby, Leonard H. "The Syntax of Gerunds in Russian." Indiana University Linguistics Club, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bache, Carl. "Aspect and Aktionsart: Towards a Semantic Distinction." Linguistics, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Bader, Francoise. "Autour de Polypheme le Cyclope a l'oeil brillant: disathese et vision." Die Sprache, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Balys, Jonas. "Suvalkiečių Laidotuvių Apeigosir Raudos." Ateitis, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Barron, T. J. "Memoir of Owen Peter Mangan, 1836-1924", 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - The Barrony of Omagh in the County of Tyrone, circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Barry, Michael V. "The English Language in Ireland." English as a World Language, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Barry, Vincent C. "The Place of the Academy in Contemporary Ireland." Royal Irish Academy Presidential Address, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Benveniste, Emile. "Une Valeur du diminutif", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Bidwell, Charles E. "The Serbo-Croatian Verb." Language, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Black, Max. "Linguistic Relativity: The Views of Benjamin Lee Whorf." Philosophical Review, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Bolinger, Dwight. "The Imperative in English." To Honor Roman Jakobson: Essays on the Occason of His Seventieth Birthday, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Briquelle, Dominique. "Initiations grecques et idéologie indo-européenne." Annales: Economies, Societés, Civilisations, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Carleton, William. Denis O'Shaughnessy Going to Maynooth (1845), circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Chaika, Elaine. "Language Lessons and Big Dan." Interfaces, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - The Church of Ireland Gazette, Sep 29, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Crist, Larrys. "Roland, héros du vouloir: contribution à l'analyse structurale de la Chanson du Roland." Mélanges de philologie et de littératures romanes offerts à Jeanne Wathelet, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Croker, T. Crofton. Researches in the South of Ireland: Illustrative of the Scenery, Architectural Remains, and the Manners and Superstitions of the Peasantry, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Dinneen, Patrick Stephen. Muinntear Ciarrade Roim an Droc-Saogal, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Dixon, R. M. W. "Ergativity." Language, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Dixon, R. M. W. "Studies in Ergativity: Introduction." Studies in Ergativity, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dixon, R. M. W. "Where Have All the Adjectives Gone?" Studies in Language, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Dubuisson, Daniel. "Le Roi indo-européen et la synthèse des trois fonctions" Annales: Economies, Sociétés, Civilisations, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Dubuisson, Daniel. "Les Talismans du roi Cormac et les trois fonctions." Revue historique, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "Bibliographie des travaux de George Dumézil", 1960 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Dybo, V. A. "Akcentologija i Slovoobrazovaniev Slavjanskom." Slavjanskoe Jazykoznanie, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Dybo, V. A. "Balto: Slavjanskaja Akcentraja Sistemas Tripologi Českoitočkizrenija i Problema Rekonstrukai Inaoevhopejskogo Akcenta." Barto-Slavjanskie Ètnojazykovye Kontakty, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Dybo, V. A. "K Klassifikaciji Srednebolgarskix Akcentrux Sistem", undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Dybo, V. A. "O Drevnejšej Metatonii v Slavjanslcom Glagole." Voprosy Jazykoznanija, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Dybo, V. A. "Sokraščrmlje Dolgot v Kelto-Ilaijskix Jazukax i Jego Značemije Dlj a Balto-Saljan-Skoj i Indo-Europejskoj Akcentologiji." Voprosy Jazykoznanija, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Dybo, V. A. "Udar Enije Slavjanskogo Glagola Foormy Startoslavjanskogo Aorista." Kratkie Soobscenija Instituta Slavjanouendanija, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Elyan, Larry. "The Irish Connection", circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Erickson, L. J. "Who Were the English and Scots Emigrants to the United States in the Late Nineteenth Century?, circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Études celtiques, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Evans, David. "Agamemnon and the Indo-European Threefold Death Pattern." History of Religions, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Fillmore, Charles J. "Deixis II.", undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Fitzgerald, Garret. "Estimates for Baronies of Minimum Level of Irish-Speaking Amongst Successive Decennial Cohorts, 1771-1781 to 1861-1871." Proceedings of the Royal Irish Academy, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Fled Bricrenn, circa 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Foster, John Wilson. "A Runagate Tongue."Causeway, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Givon, T. "A Tale of Two Passives in Ute."Passive and Voice, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Grant, William (ed). "Introduction: Phonetic Description of Scottish Language and Dialects."The Scottish National Dictory, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Gregg, Robert J. "The Scottish-Irish Dialect Boundaries in Ulster."Patterns in the Folkspeech of the British Isles, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Gregg, Robert J. The Scottish-Irish Dialect Boundaries in the Province of Ulster (I), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Gregg, Robert J. The Scottish-Irish Dialect Boundaries in the Province of Ulster (II), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Gregg, Robert J. The Scottish-Irish Dialect Boundaries in the Province of Ulster (III), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 60)